Today, I'm going to be making creamy tomato basil soup.
Let's get some of this in a bowl, and I'll show you my favorite way to present it.
If you let the soup sit for a while, what you always want to do is give it a good stir before you put it in the bowl.
You do this because some of your seasonings can sink to the bottom, or you can get a skin on top, depending on how long you let it sit.
This sat for a couple of minutes so not that much has happened to it.
I still gave it a good stir, just to make sure.
Here's our soup.
There are a couple of things I like to do with it.
I like to sprinkle just a tiny bit of balsamic vinegar; just a few drops.
It adds a nice tartness to the soup.
I like to follow that up with just a few drops of extra virgin olive oil; the good stuff, if you've got it.
Lastly, what I'll do is take a peeler and some fresh Parmesan cheese, and I'll just shave some Parmesan cheese right off the block and into the soup.
Take a peeler, and just nice, thin, wispy strands.
Don't go too deep.
That piece is a little too big, so what we'll do is break it up into some smaller pieces, just really small, light pieces.
You don't want this to overpower the soup; you want it to become part of the soup.
Toast points or roasted peppers work well on this one.
There's my fairly quick tomato basil soup.
You can make it a little faster if you use nothing but canned tomatoes; which I don't recommend.
You can actually save a lot of time on cooking them, because if you use the canned, peeled tomatoes, they don't have to break down as much.
If you're trying to make it in a hurry, that is a good way to go, but typically, you're not going to get as good of a product.
You can also mix up your tomatoes, do half yellow, half red, or do a combination of red, green, and yellow, to change the flavors.
You could garnish this with grilled green tomato, which is really nice looking.
All in all it's a really spectacular soup.
It's one of my favorites; it's very, very popular.
It goes great with grilled cheese sandwiches, which is why we all like tomato soup anyway.
Have a good one.